<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: spanish | Rebecca Sliter]]></title>
  <link href="http://rebeccasliter.com/blog/categories/spanish/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rebeccasliter.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-14T19:38:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://rebeccasliter.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rebecca Sliter]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cómo se dice...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rebeccasliter.com/blog/2013/11/14/como-se-dice-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T13:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rebeccasliter.com/blog/2013/11/14/como-se-dice-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I moved to Ecuador a few months ago I needed to learn Spanish quickly. Being surrounded by the language has been a great help; however, there are ways to fake
the immersion experience. I&rsquo;ve shared some of the tricks I used to learn
Spanish within my first month here.</p>

<p><strong>Start here: Duolingo</strong>
To improve quickly I needed to practice speaking with others, a terrifying prospect. I can&rsquo;t recommend <a href="http://www.duolingo.com/">Duolingo</a> highly enough, despite criticisms of its nonsensical phrases seemingly lacking real-world application*. The app&rsquo;s combination of drilling and silliness helped me overcome my fear of speaking Spanish with others.</p>

<p><strong>Think about it</strong>
It&rsquo;s said that dreaming in a language indicates fluency. Though I
haven&rsquo;t yet dreamt in Spanish, I&rsquo;m getting closer by forcing
translations of my thoughts.</p>

<p>Do I have a song in my head? Can I fumble through its translation, however rudimentary? Probably. When I cook, I translate the recipe in my head while prepping the food. This gives me plenty of time to mull over potential translations.</p>

<p><img src="/images/rose_gram" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>Google translate is your BFF</strong>
All those nerdy songs I was translating in my head? That time I didn&rsquo;t
know how to say <em>eggplant</em> in Spanish? I looked it up on Google
translate. Syntax-wise it&rsquo;s not perfect but I generally trust it for
single-word translations.</p>

<p><strong><em>El hombre-araña sube la rascacielo</em></strong>
Once I&rsquo;d learn a word I&rsquo;d force myself to use it in a sentence. Once again, the
sillier, the better: I remember outlandish sayings precisely because
they&rsquo;re different.</p>

<p><strong>Make it fun</strong>
I built a <a href="http://conjuegen-verbos.herokuapp.com/app/index.html#/verbos">quick Angular app</a> one day to quiz myself on translations. It didn&rsquo;t take much time to build and was fun to play with, and show off around the office, for an
afternoon. The more I incorporated Spanish into everyday activities the faster I reinforced vocabulary.</p>

<p><strong>Write it down!</strong>
I&rsquo;ve had plenty of opportunities to write emails in Spanish for work (with gratuitous
use of Google translate, of course). I&rsquo;d recommend just taking the time to write
something down in the language you&rsquo;re learning. It&rsquo;s another way to
practice using whole sentences and phrases with a real audience&mdash;
without the pressure of actually having to speak with that audience.</p>

<p><img src="/images/church_gram" /></p>

<p>As is the case with learning anything there&rsquo;s no substitute for practice. However, the tricks
I&rsquo;ve mentioned helped to make studying much more fun&mdash; and therefore,
easier.</p>

<br/>


<br/>


<p>*My personal favorite: <em>soy un pengüino</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
