<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: food | Rebecca Sliter]]></title>
  <link href="http://rebeccasliter.com/blog/categories/food/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rebeccasliter.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-14T19:39:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://rebeccasliter.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rebecca Sliter]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Literally, Wearing Many Hats]]></title>
    <link href="http://rebeccasliter.com/blog/2013/10/13/literally-wearing-many-hats/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-13T15:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rebeccasliter.com/blog/2013/10/13/literally-wearing-many-hats</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago we took a mountain-biking trip south of Quito, around
<a href="http://instagram.com/p/fGS_gSBEra/">Cotopaxí volcano</a>, ending up near a crater lake named Laguna Quilotoa. At times the temperature necessitated that I layer alpaca-wool hats in order to
not DIE OF FROSTBITE.</p>

<p><img src="/images/quilotoa_hats.jpg" /></p>

<p>Speaking of acclimation, or lack thereof, a funny thing&rsquo;s been happening
lately. In the States, travel during the workweek rendered
home-cooking impractical: it didn&rsquo;t feel right to do a huge grocery
order on a Friday evening knowing: A) that I&rsquo;d be flying Sunday afternoon, and B)
there was a Thai restaurant on the first floor of my apartment. Naturally, I elected to eat my way through the neighborhood&rsquo;s Yelp rankings, occasionally seeking out <a href="http://www.chicagoreader.com/chicago/hipster-history-of-gentrification-bohemians-logan-square/Content?oid=11117198">further-flung restaurants</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So, we&rsquo;re living here, in the same place, and in the same apartment: a
novelty for the two of us. We&rsquo;re taking advantage of this and
cooking pretty frequently. The funny thing about this? Turns out that we cook
exactly what we ordered at restaurants: pad thai and Spanish ham plates,
complicated pastas and <a href="/blog/2013/09/29/by-the-numbers">tacos</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/lilies_at_home.jpg" /></p>

<p>The best part of cooking at home is a weekly trip to Iñaquitos, a nearby market. Before going, we&rsquo;ll decide what we want to eat for the week and draw up a list: exactly the sort of ritual I was starving for during those blink-and-you&rsquo;ll-miss-it Chicago weekends.</p>

<p>Navigating Iñaquitos is another story entirely. The price of ingredients,
for example, has dropped significantly as I learn to correctly
speak Spanish outside of our office. Time in the market has also decreased as we&rsquo;ve
realized which vendors consistently stock the freshest produce. The
reward? Weekly flowers on our way out of the market, another thing I&rsquo;m
enjoying being in one place long enough to enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
